Alexander Jansing

Resume

Objective

Software Engineer and Data Scientist with two years of experience. Proficient with open source technologies supporting use of machine learning, ETL, and geospatial intelligence. Want to apply what I know on machine learning tasks and expand my knowledge base with real-world projects.

Education

2015–2019 Computer Science M.S., SUNY Polytechnic, Utica, NY, 3.67.

Focus in Algorithms and Machine Learning

Relevant courses:

Quantum Computing Al Topic: Data Science Machine Learning Formal Methods Numerical Diff Equations Parallel Computing

2012–2015 Applied Mathematics B.S., SUNY Oswego, Oswego, NY.

Focus in Computer Science and Statistics

Experience

Vocational

01/2016- Data Scientist - Computer Science, Booz Allen Hamilton, Rome, NY.

03/2018 Worked on the AFRL Active Insights project that was demoed at GeoINT2017 and will be demoed at GeoINT2018. Work focused on ETL, designing a data lake, and provenance tracking.

Technologies used For Apache Nifi ETL

Hadoop MapReduce and Archiving
Accumulo Primary database storage
Docker DevOps and containerizing work

Spring Boot Creating REST services
Deep Detect Image identification

2015–2016 Graduate Assistant, SUNY Polytechnic, Utica, NY.

Graded homework, held office hours, and designed grading schemes for Finite Mathematics.

Miscellaneous

2012–2018 MQ-9 Avionics Technician, 174th Fighter Wing, Syracuse, NY.

2009–2012 F-16 Avionics Technician, United States Air Force, Phoenix, AZ.

Computer skills

Languages Java, Python, Languages Lang

Databases Accumulo, OrientDB, TitanDB, MongoDB, Postgres, Hadoop

Systems Linux (CentOS and Ubuntu), Mac, Windows

Technologies Git, Jira, Confluence, Nifi, AWS, Maven, Docker, Docker Compose

Presentations

October 2016 An Overview and Brief Tutorial of Niagara Files.

Presented to Booz Allen Hamilton's internal webcast and conference line.

Description Niagara Files (Nifi) is a digraph ETL program that provides a web-based UI, loss tolerance, data provenance, and the ability to create custom processors using a Maven archetype. Covered what a FlowFile is and some of the most important concepts of Nifi that are needed to understand before working with Nifi.

May 2015 Lie Algebras.

Presented to SUNY Oswego Mathematics Department.

Description Lie algebras have two special operators, the Lie bracket and the inner product and they both have special characteristics that impose algebraic and geometry restrictions on the spaces they apply to. We looked at how they interact, and wrote programs in ${\rm SAGE}~({\rm PYTHON})$ that generate general forms of the matrix representations of these interactions.